ccpsnet.net 2018-05-11

# Internet Privacy Statement | Chesterfield County Public Schools

**Chesterfield County Public Schools  
****Internet Privacy Policy Statement** ** **

**Modified July 11, 2012** ** **

The following information explains the Internet Privacy Policy Chesterfield County Public Schools has adopted for its mychesterfieldschools.com Web site. The following is intended to explain our current Internet privacy practices but shall not be construed as a contractual promise. We reserve the right to amend our Internet Privacy Policy and Internet Privacy Policy Statement at any time without notice.

**Virginia Law**

We maintain our records in accordance with our obligations as defined by applicable Virginia statutes, including, but not limited to, the “ **The Government Data Collection and Dissemination Policies** **Act** ,” the “Virginia Public Records Act,” and by any applicable U.S. Federal laws.

**Links to Other Web Sites**

Because Chesterfield County Public Schools cannot control the sites to which we link, it cannot be held responsible for content included in them. Moreover, in no way should an external link be considered any form of endorsement by Chesterfield County Public Schools.

Information contained on mychesterfieldschools.com provides links that are maintained by other public and private organizations. Because Chesterfield County Public Schools cannot control or guarantee the accuracy, relevance, timeliness, or completeness of sites to which it links, Chesterfield County Public Schools cannot be responsible for their content. Further, the inclusion of pointers to particular items in hypertext is not intended to reflect their importance, nor is it intended to endorse any views expressed or products or services offered by the author of the reference or the organization operating the server on which the reference is maintained.

**Cookies Policy**

Cookies are small temporary pieces of data held in your computer and do not collect any personally identifiable information about you, the user, while visiting our site.

Persistent cookies are small permanent pieces of data stored by your computer on your hard disk and typically expire after some designated time frame.

Mychesterfieldschools.com discourages the use of Web cookies on its Web site, however, temporary or transient cookies may be used when necessary to complete a transaction. Certain services within our site use cookies to enhance the user experience. Any information collected on our Web site including information from persistent Web cookies is generally subject to Virginia Access to Public Records Law except as otherwise provided by Virginia or federal law. Mychesterfieldschools.com makes use of temporary or transient cookies to do things like maintain continuity from page to page or populate a form field within our site. These transient cookies are held only in the memory of your machine temporarily and vanish as soon as you close your browser.

**Information We Collect** ** **

When you access our Web site , **Routing information**  (the Internet domain and Internet address of the computer you are using,) **Essential technical information**   (identification of the page or service you are requesting, type of browser and operating system you are using; and the date and time of access) and **Nonessential technical information**  (the Internet address of the Web site from which you linked directly to our Web site) is automatically collected. No other information is collected through our Web site.

When you deliberately decide to send information (for example, by clicking on a link to send us an email, the information you might choose to send us is **optional information** or when you fill out online forms) all the data you choose to fill in or confirm is **optional information**.

**Usage of Data Collected on Our Web Site**

Some of the services that we provide require personal information to be sent to us via Chesterfield County Public Schools Web site, mychesterfieldschools.com. We will not use or share the information collected on our site in ways unrelated to the purpose for which you provided the information. Chesterfield County Public Schools will use your information only to fulfill your requests for certain services, or to personalize your experience on our Web site.

If you do nothing during your visit but browse through the mychesterfieldschools.com Web site to read Web pages or download information, mychesterfieldschools.com will automatically gather and store certain information about your visit. Your Web browser software transmits most of this information to us; however, this information does not identify you personally. 

We automatically collect and store only the following information about your visit:

  * The numeric IP address (an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the Web) from which you access the mychesterfieldschools.com Site. Mychesterfieldschools.com software can then map these IP addresses into Internet domain names, for example, “xcompany.com” if you use a private Internet access account, or “yourschool.edu” if you connect from a university’s domain;
  * The type of browser and operating system used to access the mychesterfieldschools.com Site;
  * The date and time you access the mychesterfieldschools.com Site;
  * The pages you visit, including graphics loaded from each page and other documents you download, such as PDF (Portable Document Format) files and word processing documents; and

If you send us e-mail, you should know that e-mail is not necessarily secure against interception. If your communication includes sensitive information (like your bank account, credit card, or social security number) please contact the appropriate county personnel via postal mail or telephone, rather than e-mail (see contacting the Web Site below.)

From time to time, we may be required to provide to others personally identifiable information which you have provided to us in response to a court order, Freedom of Information request, subpoena, or government investigation. We also reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we, in good faith, believe to be unlawful. We may disclose certain personally identifiable information when we believe that such release is reasonable, necessary to enforce or apply our terms and/or conditions, or to protect the rights, property and safety of others or ourselves.

Please be aware that Web sites that have links on our site may collect personally identifiable information about you. This privacy statement does not cover the information practices of those parties and Web sites linked to mychesterfieldschools.com.

**Security**

Chesterfield County has security in place to protect against the loss, misuse or unauthorized alteration of information under our control. This security includes:

  * **Firewalls**
  * **Secured Socket Shell (SSH)**
  * **Secured File Transfer Protocol (SFTP)**

**Contacting the Web Site**

If you have general questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this Web site, your experience with this Web site, or if you chose to review or correct any information previously submitted, contact the Webmaster.
